Guide to the Early Rice Institute records, 1844-1941 UA 101
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series I: Court cases, 1886-1907 (Boxes 1-50), 241813
  - Subseries C: Baldwin vs. Rice, 1886-1908 (Boxes 41-49), 241823
    - 1907, 241835
      - Memorandum on order presented for settlement by plaintiffs (includes list of which descendants received what amounts of money), 241842 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Memoranda regarding Answer, 241841 (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Summary of papers mentioned in letter by Baker, Botts, Parker & Garwood, Jan. 21, 1904, 241840 (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Memoranda regarding costs, 241839 (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Assignment from Marian Roberts Robinson and Beverly Robinson to William Marsh Rice Institute, 1907 ($8,533.33), 241838 (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Published briefs, 241837 (Box 47, Folder 10)
      - Published data re. appeals, 241836 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Baldwin v. Rice Legal correspondence, 241824
      - 1901, 241834 (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - 1902, 241833 (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - 1903, 241832 (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - 1904, Jan. – Mar., 241831 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - 1904, Apr. – Dec., 241830 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - 1905, 241829 (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - 1906, 241828 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - 1907, 241827 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - 1908, 241826 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - n.d., 241825 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Subseries D: Other cases, 1900-1904 (Box 50), 241814
    - Baldwin et al v. Holt, 241822 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Baldwin v. O'Brien, n.d., 241821 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Adolph Black v. John T. Milliken, Nov. 24, 1902, 241820 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Affidavit of A.T. Patrick in case of Theodore R. Carter against Phillipine C. Allen, July 1900, 241819 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - William D. Chase v. Knickerbocker Phosphate Co., Synopsis of brief of Logan, Demond & Hardy, 241818 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Sallie Currie v. James A. Baker Jr. et al as executors of the last will and testament of William M. Rice, 241817 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Swenson & Sons v. Rice, 1904, 241816 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Weatherbee v. Baker / Zeamens v. Baker, 241815 (Box 50, Folder 8)
- Series II: WMR will & estate, 1900-1911 (Boxes 51-87), 241596
  Includes litigation records related to proving of 1896 Wm. M. Rice will, probate of estate, temporary administration of estate, estate appraisal and taxes, land deeds and titles, inventory of property, correspondence, releases from Rice relatives, judicial settlement of estate and more.
  - Subseries A: 1900, 241798
    - Original letter from C.F. Jones to Capt. Baker, regarding Rice will, Jan. 18, 1900, 241812 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Will, William Marsh Rice, June 30, 1900, Albert T. Patrick named as co-executor (forged will), 241811 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Deed for Harris County property sold by A.T. Patrick to James A. Baker, Jr. and R.S. Lovett, Feb. 6, 1900, 241810 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Writ of prohibition, June 1900, 241809 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Crematory certificate for Wm. M. Rice cremation Sept. 27, 1900, certificate dated 1909, and including note by A.B. Cohn regarding a copy of same certificate being buried in Rice monument on Rice campus, and copy of Aug. 3, 1900 letter from Rice stating his wish to be cremated., 241808 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Application for Temporary Administration of Rice estate, James A. Baker, Jr., Sept. 28-29, 1900. Also includes documents related to Rice Ranch, First Presbyterian Church, merchants and Planters Oil Company, and other persons and businesses related to Rice's estate, 1900-1901, 241807 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Land deeds from W.M. Rice to Foster and Magnum, Sept. 1900, 241806 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Lawsuit: First Division City Magistrates' Court, First District, New York, October 15, 1900: The People, on Complaint of Arthur A. Carey vs. A.T. Patrick and Charles F. Jones, Offense Charged: Forgery. Relates to $25,00 check written by Patrick in Rice's name. Testimony transcript., 241805 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Proving of Last Will & Testament, 1900, 241804 (Box 51, Folder 8-9)
    - Statements re. estate (Patrick, Jones, & others), 1900, 241803 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Estate administration, 1900, 241802 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, general, 241801 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Notes, memoranda, 241800 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Nina Belle Rice (infant relative) notes, 241799 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Subseries B: 1901, 241772
    - Discovery, 241797 (Box 52, Folder 6-8)
    - Agreements and petitions with relatives, 241796 (Box 53, Folder 1-3)
    - Agreements, 241795 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Citations, 241794 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Proving of will of 1896 – notes, precedent, 241793 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Proving of will of 1896, 241792 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Proving of will of 1896, 241791 (Box 54, Folder 1-4)
    - Proving of will of 1896, 241790 (Box 55, Folder 1-3)
    - Administration of estate after death of Frederick A. Rice, 241789 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Administration of estate, 241788 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Order for Publication of Citation & Notice of Entry, filed by Albert T. Patrick, executor named in June 30, 1900 will of Wm. M. Rice, on Jan. 16, 1901, 241787 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Estate activity, Galveston, la Porte & Houston Rwy. Co., March 1901, 241786 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Petition for appointment of H. Baldwin Rice as Permanent Administrator, March, 1901, 241785 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Petitions for appointment of Frederick A. Rice (brother of Wm. M. Rice) as Permanent Administrator, March, 1901, 241784 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Answer of William M. Rice Institute, March 9, 1901, 241783 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Documents related to Frederick A. Rice (brother of Wm. M. Rice) as Permanent Administrator of estate, March 26, 1901, 241782 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Final report of Baker as Temporary Administrator of estate, Mar. 27, 1901, 241781 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Estate activity: April 1901, 241780 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - April 1901: Merchants and Planters Oil Company: Charter, Articles of Incorporation, description of real and personal property ca. 1901, request for loan from estate to rebuild mill after damage from earlier Galveston storm, 241779 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Harris County, Application for Letters of Temporary Administration of Wm. M. Rice estate, by H. Baldwin Rice, April 12, 1901, 241778 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Surrogate's Court, NY: Affidavit of James A. Baker, Jr., April 15, 1901, 241777 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Surrogate's Court, NY: Affidavit of Regularity, Wm. M. Wherry for attys. Hornblower, Byrne, Miller & Potter (HBM&P), May 1901, 241776 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Surrogate's Court, NY: Petition of John D. Bartine (HBM&P) for an order directing notice of hearing, May 8, 1901, 241775 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Temporary Administration of estate, 1901, 241774 (Box 56, Folder 14-16)
    - Estate bills receivable, 241773 (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - Subseries C: 1901-1902, 241757
    - Probate Proceedings transcripts, Surrogate's Court. Hon. Frank T. Fitzgerald: Beginning Monday April 8th, 1901 (or is it April 1902) – Apr. 17, 1902, N.Y., 241771 (Box 57, Folder 1-2)
    - Probate Proceedings, Vol II: Beginning June 11, 1902, 241770 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - NY papers & Probate Statements, 241769 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Probate memoranda, 241768 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Probate correspondence, notes, 241767 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Probate proceedings re. will, 241766 (Box 58, Folder 3-4)
    - Authorities, 241765 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Bound volume of transcripts of probate testimony, 241764 (Box 115, Folder -)
    - Probate, general, 241763 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Estate pleadings, 241762 (Box 59, Folder 2-3)
    - Correspondence, 241761 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Temporary Administration, 241760 (Box 59, Folder 5-8)
    - Proving of last will and testament, 241759 (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Proving of last will and testament, 241758 (Box 60, Folder 1-5)
  - Subseries D: 1902, 241738
    - Temporary Administration of estate, 241756 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Temporary Administration of estate, 241755 (Box 61, Folder 1-3)
    - Agreements, 241754 (Box 61, Folder 4-5)
    - Relatives (powers of attorneys, etc.), 241753 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Writ of Prohibition against 1900 will, 241752 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Writ of Prohibition against 1900 will, 241751 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Administration, including correspondence re. $7 million bond, 241750 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Estate inventory and appraisal, Feb. 19, 1902, 241749 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Alternative writ of prohibition, 241748 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Writ of Prohibition, 241747 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Judicial settlement of estate, incl. Letter from Patrick to Baker demanding return of estate items, 241746 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Albert T. Patrick appeal, 241745 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Land deeds, 1902-1904, 241744 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Deeds in Holt settlement, 241743 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 241742 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Financial documents and land deeds, 241741 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Proving of last will and testament, 241740 (Box 63, Folder 6-9)
    - New Jersey tax, 241739 (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Subseries E: 1903, 241730
    - Request for trial regarding 1896 v. 1900 will, 241737 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Estate appraisal, 241736 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Proving of Last Will and Testament, 241735 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 241734 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Administration, 241733 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Estate pleadings, 1903-1904, 241732 (Box 64, Folder 6-7)
    - Memoranda, 241731 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Subseries F: 1904, 241717
    - Correspondence, 241729 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, financial, 241728 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Statement for cash paid for insurance, taxes, and improvements to the Elkwood property, 241727 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Tax appraisal, 241726 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - N.Y. Tax / Baker deposition, 241725 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Report of Disposition of Amounts Paid in Settlement by Rice Institute, 241724 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Judicial settlement of account of executors, March-April, 1904, 241723 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Judicial settlement, 241722 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Judicial settlement, 241721 (Box 66, Folder 1-2)
    - Settlement of estate, 241720 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Final accounting, 241719 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Other litigation papers (Zeamans v. Rice estate, Weatherbee v. Rice estate), 241718 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Subseries G: 1905, 241714
    - Appraisal, 241716 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Releases, 241715 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Subseries H: 1907, 241711
    - Judicial settlement & various notes, 241713 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Estate of Dr. Curry v. Rice, 241712 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Subseries I: 1907, 241694
    - Relatives' authorizations for attorneys, 241710 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Indemnity documents, 241709 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - Relatives' assignments and releases, 241708 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Relatives' assignments and releases, 241707 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Releases and receipts, 241706 (Box 67, Folder 2-3)
    - Unused forms of decree for final settlement, Sept. 17, 1907, 241705 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Judicial settlement of estate, 241704 (Box 67, Folder 5-7)
    - Decree finally settling account and ordering distribution, 241703 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Settlement regarding assignment of bonds and release for surety companies, 241702 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Settlement of Minerva Olds trust, 241701 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Settlement of Drawing Room Society of N.Y., including information on Louisiana lands, 241700 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - General assignment of assets, 241699 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Receipts for sums paid to relatives, 241698 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Receipts and releases, 241697 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Releases and assignments, 241696 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Memorandum for Mr. Byrne, 241695 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Receipt for papers received, Feb. 14, 1908, 241693 (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Subseries J: 1910, 241690
    - People v. Patrick as related to Rice estate, 241692 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Trust funds, 1904-1910, 241691 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Subseries K: 1911, 241671
    - Memoranda for Mr. Byrne, 241689 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence re. pardon of Patrick, effect on estate, Oct. 13, 1909-1915, 241688 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Memoranda re. Patrick, 241687 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Nina Belle Rice business, 241686 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Notes regarding personal property in Texas, 241685 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Divorce research, general, 241684 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Notes and discovery re forgery, 1900-1907, 241683 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Accounting of papers and their whereabouts, 241682 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Time account, Sept. 29, 1900-July 6, 1903, 241681 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Mr. Byrne's opinion, 1912, re. Section 2563 of code, & incl. Correspondence re. forgeries, 241680 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Estate notes, n.d., 241679 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Memoranda, 241678 (Box 70, Folder 6-7)
    - Memoranda, 241677 (Box 71, Folder 1-3)
    - Memoranda, 241676 (Box 72, Folder 1-6)
    - Memoranda, 241675 (Box 73, Folder 1-5)
    - Various published portions of estate litigation, 241674 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Various published portions of estate litigation, proof of law, 241673 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Published briefs (2 bound volumes), 241672 (Box 115, Folder -)
  - Subseries L: Estate Correspondence, general, 241659
    - October 1, 1900-December 1901, and n.d., 241670 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Jan.-March, 1901, 241669 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - April-June, 1901, 241668 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - July- Sept., 1901, 241667 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Oct.-Dec., 1901, 241666 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - HBM&P and BBB&L correspondence, March - April 1901, 241665 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - 1902, 241664 (Box 76, Folder 1-2)
    - Estate settlement, 1902, 241663 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - April-Sept., 1902, 241662 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Oct.-Dec., 1902, 241661 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 1903, 241660 (Box 77, Folder 1-2)
  - Subseries M: >Baker correspondence (incoming and outgoing carbons, including 1900 mss notebooks), 241627
    - Sept. 24-30, 1900, 241658 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Oct. 1-8, 1900, 241657 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Oct. 9-14, 1900, 241656 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Oct. 5-20, 1900, 241655 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Notebooks, ca. 1900, 241654 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Oct. 21-31, 1900, 241653 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Nov. 1-15, 1900, 241652 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Nov. 16-30, 1900, 241651 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Dec., 1900, 241650 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Jan., 1901, 241649 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Feb., 1901, 241648 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - March, 1901, 241647 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - April, 1901, 241646 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - May, 1901, 241645 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - June-Aug., 1901, 241644 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Sept.-Oct., 1901, 241643 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Nov.-Dec., 1901, 241642 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - January, 1902, 241641 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Feb., 1902, 241640 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - March, 1902, 241639 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - April-May, 1902, 241638 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - June, 1902, 241637 (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - July, 1902, 241636 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - August, 1902, 241635 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Sept., 1902, 241634 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - October, 1902, 241633 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Nov., 1902, 241632 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Dec., 1902, 241631 (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - 1906, 241630 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - 1907, 241629 (Box 82, Folder 2-4)
    - 1911-1914, 241628 (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Subseries N: H.B. Rice files, Temp. & Perm. Administration, 1901-1906, 241620
    - Dec. 1901 – Feb. 1902, 241626 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - March – Sept., 1902, 241625 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Oct.-Dec., 1902, 241624 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Jan.-Sept., 1903, 241623 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Oct. 1903 – Dec. 1904, 241622 (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - 1906-1912, 241621 (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - Subseries O: N.Y. Executors, 1902-1904, 241610
    - 1902, 241619 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Jan. – May, 1903, 241618 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - June – Nov. 1903, 241617 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Dec. 1903 – Feb. 1904, 241616 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - March – May, 1904, 241615 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - June-Dec., 1904, 241614 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - 1905, 241613 (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - 1906, 241612 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - 1907, 241611 (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Subseries P: NY Executors/TX Administrators, 1902-1904, 241607
    - Dec. 30, 1902 – April, 1903, 241609 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - May 1903 – April 1904, 241608 (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Subseries Q: Texas Administrators: probate of will correspondence, 241600
    - Legal documents and correspondence, 241606 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Sept. 1903-Dec. 1904, 241605 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Jan.-July, 1905, 241604 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Aug.-Dec., 1905, 241603 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Jan.-June, 1906, 241602 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - July 1906 - Oct. 1907, 241601 (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Subseries R: Suits against the Rice Institute (as Rice estate), 241597
    - Harrison County v. Rice Institute, 1906-07, 241599 (Box 87, Folder 1-3)
    - Rice Institute v. Lena Geiseke, 1905-1914, 241598 (Box 87, Folder 4-6)
- Series III: Rice Institute, 1882-1941 (bulk 1891-1918) (Boxes 88-97, 116), 241489
  This series includes documentation of early Rice Board of Trustees activities, revealing some of the very first attempts to shape the Institute. Correspondence, particularly with Capt. James A. Baker, Board meeting minutes, financial documents, loan documents showing how Rice Institute acted as a bank for real estate and business ventures, and Board research on charitable institutions and other universities' and colleges' charters and reports.
  - Subseries A: General Correspondence (primarily with Baker Botts Baker and Lovett), 1882-1918, 241563
    - 1882 WMR Will, 241595 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - 1893 WMR Will, 241594 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Letters and papers, 1891-1889, 241593 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - 1900, Swenson Bank checks, 241592 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Letters and papers, 1900-1901, 241591 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Letters and papers, 1902-1903, 241590 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Letters and papers, 1904-1906, 241589 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Letters and papers, after transfer, Sept.-Dec., 1906, 241588 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Letters and papers, after transfer, Jan. – Mar., 1907, 241587 (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Letters and papers, after transfer, Apr.-July, 1907, 241586 (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - Letters and papers, 1907, 241585 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Letters and papers, Jan.-April, 1908, 241584 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Letters and papers, May-Dec., 1908, 241583 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Letters and papers, transfers, 1908, 241582 (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Inventories, 1908, 241581 (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Letters and papers, Jan.-June, 1909, 241580 (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Letters and papers, July-Nov., 1909, 241579 (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Letters and papers, Dec. 1909 – Nov. 1910, 241578 (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Letters and papers, Dec. 1910 – Apr. 1911, 241577 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Letters and papers, May-August, 1911, 241576 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Letters and papers, Oct. 1911 – Oct. 1912, 241575 (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Letters and papers, Nov. 1912 – April 1913, 241574 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Letters and papers, May – Sept. 1913, 241573 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Letters and papers, Oct. 1913 – Feb. 1914, 241572 (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Letters and papers, March – August, 1914, 241571 (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Letters and papers, Sept. 1914 – Feb. 1915, 241570 (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - Letters and papers, March – July 1915, 241569 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Letters and papers, Sept. 1915 – Jan. 1916, 241568 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Letters and papers, Feb. – Sept. 1916, 241567 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Letters and papers, Oct. 1916 – Jan. 1917, 241566 (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Letters and papers, Feb. – Sept. 1917, 241565 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Letters and papers, Oct. 1917 – July 1918, 241564 (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - Subseries B: Financial correspondence, 1907-1941, 241560
    - Financial correspondence, 1907-1908, 241562 (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - Financial correspondence, 1908-1912, 1928-1941, 241561 (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Subseries C: Loans from Rice Institute, 241529
    Dates reflect the dates of the documents, not necessarily the range of dates of the loans.
    - Loan: Mrs. Elizabeth Achenbach et al, 1913, 241559 (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Loan: Austin College, 1913-1919, 241558 (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Purchase from R.H. Baker, 1914, 241557 (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Loan: S.F. Carter, 1914, 241556 (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - Loan: Andrew Dow, 1913, 241555 (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Loan: L.A. Hamburger & Gus Dreyling, 1909, 241554 (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Extension agreement: Edgewood Realty Co. & Southern Loan and Investment Co., 1910-1920, 241553 (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - Loan: First M. E. Church South, 1911, 241552 (Box 92, Folder 8)
    - Lots: M.E. Foster, 1914, 241551 (Box 92, Folder 9)
    - Loan: Ella S. Heyer, 1911, 241550 (Box 92, Folder 10)
    - Loan: Bettie Palmer M. Hutcheson, 1914, 241549 (Box 92, Folder 11)
    - Loan: Jesse Jones and Southern Loan and Investment Co., 1913, 241548 (Box 92, Folder 12)
    - Substitute of Collateral by Jesse Jones and Southern Loan and Investment Co., 1914-1917, 241547 (Box 92, Folder 13)
    - Loan: Jesse Jones, 1916-1917, 241546 (Box 92, Folder 14)
    - Jesse Jones Application for Exchange Security, Chronicle Bonds, 1918-1922, 241545 (Box 92, Folder 15)
    - Loan: August E. Kutschbach, 1914, 241544 (Box 92, Folder 16)
    - Loan: Louisa Jones, 1917, 241543 (Box 92, Folder 17)
    - Deed: Guardian Trust Co. to Rice Institute, 1920, 241542 (Box 92, Folder 18)
    - Masterson v. Rice Institute, 1894-1906, 241541 (Box 93, Folder 1-2)
    - Loan: George T. Moore, 1913, 241540 (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Indebtedness of Merchants and Planters Oil Co., 1916-1918, 241539 (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - Loan: George W. Norrell, 1914-1916, 241538 (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Loan: Mrs. S.M. Palmer, 1914, 241537 (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - Loan: H.B. Rice, 1909, 241536 (Box 93, Folder 7)
    - Loan: Mrs. M.E. Roberts, 1913-1914, 241535 (Box 93, Folder 8)
    - Loan: J.D. and Ellen B. Ross, 1910-1913, 241534 (Box 93, Folder 9)
    - Loan: Settegast Realty Co., 1913-1914, 241533 (Box 93, Folder 10)
    - Extension: John S. Stuart & Mrs. Rachel B. Stewart, 1910-1913, 241532 (Box 93, Folder 11)
    - Extension of note: G.C. Street, 1914-1929, 241531 (Box 93, Folder 12)
    - Wm. M. Rice note ($200,000) payable to Rice Institute, and Deed of gift document original and 1 copy from William M. Rice to James A. Baker et al, trustees, for the use of the William M. Rice Institute for the Advancement of Literature, Science and Art., 241530 (Box 93, Folder 13)
  - Subseries D: Officer files, 241521
    - A.B. Cohn, Asst. Sec. to Board, and Business Manager, files, 1901-1934, 241528 (Box 94, Folder 1-4)
    - E. Raphael, Secretary, Rice Institute, 241522
      - Clippings, 1910-1912, 241527 (Box 94, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, 1891-1913, 241526 (Box 94, Folder 6-8)
      - Dickens Fellowship clippings, 241525 (Box 94, Folder 9)
      - Raphael Bros., business documents, 1908-1909, 241524 (Box 94, Folder 10)
      - West Texas oil correspondence and reports, A.L. Raphael, 1931-1954, 241523 (Box 94, Folder 11)
  - Subseries E: Chronological files, 241500
    Correspondence, financial notes.
    - 1891, 241520 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - 1892, 241519 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - 1893, 241518 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - 1894, 241517 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - 1895, 241516 (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - 1896, 241515 (Box 95, Folder 6)